hey everyone welcome back to the stores
automation playlist and we are talking
about Tosca best practices
now this is the fifth video in the
series so if you have not watched the
previous ones go to the playlist and
watch all of these previous videos
now coming to the best practice number
five but before we start I would also
recommend you to subscribe to our
channel so that you don't miss out on
all the future videos uh as soon as we
upload them okay
so this best practice is talking about
no mouse or keyboard methods so minimize
the methods which are related to mouse
or keyboard and these are basically uh
it could be any method it could be some
key combinations from a keyboard or it
could be a mouse click right and you can
use them in some of the methods like the
send Keys method okay and it is very
common uh whenever you want to click on
a button or a link you generally use
this click method okay or you want to
send some key key combinations through
your keyboard you in your send Keys
method you use all these key
combinations right so you have to
understand that Tosca is trying to
simulate this uh keystrokes from your
keyboard or the click buttons from the
mouse right using this methods which is
defined in the Microsoft Keys okay so
these are basically Keys which are
defined by Microsoft which works in a
Windows based operating system right so
uh that's what Tosca is doing and for
that uh it needs to connect to different
apis through which it can basically
perform this particular operation all
right but you have to understand due to
the complexity of this uh it may not be
the best way to do this okay so
generally uh it is much slower and not
so stable okay so you can still use this
method but uh class centers recommends
that you minimize the use of this or you
use something else okay for example if
you are using this click method instead
of that you can put a x now this x is
doing the same thing as a click method
so it will perform the click on a button
or on a link right but it is much faster
and also considered more stable okay
so you have to take care of these things
whenever you are designing your test
case and in your test steps I try to use
the more efficient and more faster
methods instead of the regular methods
okay
so let's try to look at an example okay
a real-time example on how this can be
done so in our last uh best practice we
were talking about the sweet on method
right and in this test case you can see
I have used uh The Click method okay
to click on this particular buttons like
calculate and send and it works
absolutely fine you may not even notice
the difference if I use something else
but uh in the long run when you are
executing long lot of test cases a small
change or a small Improvement in the
execution could help you immensely right
so it can speed up your execution your
execution time could come down okay so
you have to take care of a small things
in order to make your uh test set more
efficient Okay so so instead of this
click method uh what we can do is we can
write X here okay
and the same I can do it here
and as you can see uh it is going to
perform the same operation okay so let's
run this and let's verify this so I'm
going to run this now and it should work
exactly the same as it was working
earlier okay
so let's see uh if it is still working
the same using
um this particular method instead of the
mouse or keyboard method right
so it is clicked on the calculate button
uh you've watched it
the difference you will see that the
mouse pointer has not moved to the
button because Tosca is not actually
simulating the mouse and keyboard
movements okay so it is doing this
internally and that's why I said this
method is much faster because it is not
a UI interaction right it is doing that
internally so it is much faster than
simulating the exact way a human does it
right like we take the mouse pointer and
then we click on a particular button
right so that's the simulation which is
performed when you use a keyboard or
Mouse method but if you use something
else then it will be much faster right
because you don't need to do that on the
UI okay so to conclude Transcendence
recommends that don't use or minimize
the use of uh the mouse and keyboard
methods instead of this try to find a
more efficient and faster method okay
so that's all for this video I hope you
like it and you enjoyed it
um there are lots more videos coming up
on our channel so keep watching and keep
learning